<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Methods</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/post/</link><description>Recent content on Methods</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="cloudnativemethods.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Engineering Productivity Goals</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/ep-goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:23:59 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/ep-goals/</guid><description>Connect all of the software delivery activities to measurable business outcomes
Empower application operators to deploy services, both stateless and stateful, without human intervention.
Enable a consistent way for services to describe events within event-driven architectures.
Enable safe and optimized default behaviors for platform capabilities wherever possible.
Provide a developer-centric PR based approach towards testing and test frameworks with fast feedback loops.</description></item><item><title>Personas</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/personas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:23:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/personas/</guid><description>Developers Developers are the domain experts on the business logic and write code for the application. They are responsible for describing what a microservice does and how it can be configured. They are typically not concerned with where the micoservice is deployed.
Application Operators Application Operators are domain experts on the platform. They are responsible for configuring the runtim aspects of these microservices. In many use cases, application operator could be the platform itself.</description></item><item><title>Workloads</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/workloads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:23:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/workloads/</guid><description>Container A Container is a workload that runs OCI containers: Docker, containerd, CRI-O.
Functions Functions as in Function as a Service is an event driven model that allows execution of discreet modular code in a serverless computing environment. A few examples of the more commonly deployed Function as a Service (FaaS) platforms include Knative, OpenFaaS and AWS Firecracker.
VM A virtual machine is a workload that operates on top of a hypervisor and contains its own virtualized hardware stack comprising of network adapters, storage, RAM, CPU with applications, binaries, and libraries.</description></item><item><title>Application Delivery</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/app-delivery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:22:59 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/app-delivery/</guid><description>Target Goals 1 - Connect all of the software delivery activities to measurable business outcomes.
2 - Empower application operators to deploy services, both stateless and stateful, without human intervention
In order to achieve the above goals, the focus for the application delivery framework should be flow over siloed specializations. The open source OAM spec will be used as the foundational building block on which the framework will be built upon.</description></item><item><title>Architectural Characteristics</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/arch-chars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:22:59 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/arch-chars/</guid><description>Architecture is abstract until it is operationalized. &amp;mdash; Neal Ford Characteristic Vs Trait According to Merriam-Webster&amp;rsquo;s dictionary, one of the definitions of the word characteristic is a quality or property of a person or thing and the definition of the word trait is an inherited characteristic of a person or thing
Within the context of software architecture, we could view a characteristic as a generalization of one or more traits that can be applied to a wide range of concerns critical to the success of the architecture.</description></item><item><title>Performance Engineering</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/perf-eng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:21:59 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/perf-eng/</guid><description>Runtime performance optimization Developing libraries and tools for understanding and optimizing runtime performance of different applications. Supporting teams with comprehensive analysis of runtime performance and the implications for overall system performance. Accelarating application performance Standardizing and accelerating parts of the application stack. Analyzing system performance and advising teams on runtime budgets and avoiding performance regressions. Assisting development teams Supporting development of new features to ensure acceptable runtime performance.</description></item><item><title>Test Engineering</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/test-eng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:20:59 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/test-eng/</guid><description>Unit Testing Provide frameworks to test individual units (e.g. functions) to verify that they work correctly.
Utility functions that are modular, relatively independent of other code should be verified to work by passing in user-defined inputs.
Automated software testing Increase the depth and scope of tests to improve software quality.
Provide robust automation test frameworks to support execution of different complex test case scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Chaos Engineering</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/chaos-eng/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:19:59 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/chaos-eng/</guid><description>Coming soon&amp;hellip;
Experiments
Temperature
Health checks</description></item><item><title>Auto Scaling Trait</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/autoscaling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:05:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/autoscaling/</guid><description>Coming soon&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Ingress Trait</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/ingress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:05:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/ingress/</guid><description>Coming soon&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Logging Trait</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/logging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:05:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/logging/</guid><description>Coming soon&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Monitoring Trait</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:05:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/monitoring/</guid><description>Coming soon&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Secrets Trait</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/secrets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:05:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/secrets/</guid><description>Coming soon&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Tracing Trait</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/tracing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:05:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/tracing/</guid><description>Coming soon&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Platform Infrastructure Goals</title><link>cloudnativemethods.com/pi-goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 21:04:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>cloudnativemethods.com/pi-goals/</guid><description> Compute
Network
Storage
Subnets
Base Container Image builds
Scanning Infrastructure</description></item></channel></rss>